CERTIFIED ADVANCED FACILITATOR

Summary

Project Manager effective in leading and directing IT infrastructure and software development projects from inception to launch. More than 15 years of progressive management experience and repeated success in developing project initiatives, directing project plans and achieving revenue performance targets.

Highlights

- Certified PMP (#1931443)
- Project Vision, Strategy, Governance & Management
- · Risk management
- Vendor sourcing

- Systems implementation
- SDLC / Waterfall
- Agile / Scrum
- Software ArchitectureÂ
- Requirements Elicitation

Experience

01/2002 to Current

Certified Advanced Facilitator Caci International Inc. i1/4 Fort Washington, MD

- Serve as subject matter expert for Software Architecture courses, developing course objectives and curriculum used by all instructors of
 course.
- Teaching duties include upper-level and graduate-level systems development courses, including Critical Thinking and Computer Logic, SQL for Business, Business Systems Development, Intro to Programming C++, Software Architecture.

01/2001 to Current

Technology & Security Manager Cleveland Clinic il/4 Westlake, OH

- 15 years' experience in IT projects for business process outsourcing (BPO) firm.
- Managed small to large-scale IT projects, leading local and virtual teams in matrix organization to deliver application development, IT infrastructure, and service management projects.
- Systems development using agile and SDLC/waterfall methodologies from project conception through delivery.
- Authored proposals, project management plans, implementation plans.
- Analyzed and evaluated project efficacy with proof of concept analysis, build vs.
- buy determination, elicitation and documentation of functional and non-functional requirements.
- Partnered with clients to gain acceptance of schedules, requirements, and deliverables.
- Participated in client joint application development (JAD sessions), addressed client inquiries, conducted and reported official root cause analysis for technical issues.
- Negotiate with client's change management team to coordinate change requests and implementations.
- Evaluated and aligned resources to prioritize resource utilization based on importance, constraints, and deadlines.
- Identified, assessed, tracked, and responded to project risk factors.
- Measured, verified, and communicated project performance (time, scope, budget, quality) against planned values.
- Representative Projects: Technical product manager for globally accessible payment processing system.
- Chaired change board for maintenance within operating budget, focusing on changing and additional requirements.
- Led projects for development of a suite of 12 integrated applications to replace and enhance existing systems.
- Developed payment processing application for use by small employers to submit payments electronically through Automated Clearing House (ACH) network.
- System provided significant productivity gains and increased accuracy over manual processes.
- Software and solution design team member for payment processing components of Nevada HealthLink (health exchange) contract.
- Several 1+ year assignments as technical implementation manager for integrating new internal systems with interfaces to existing client
 systems; one replacing outgoing service provider, requiring integration of previous vendor's data into internal system and integration with
 client system.

01/2000 to 01/2001

Technical Lead Brown & Brown, Inc. il/4 Charlotte, NC

- Supervised programming team in developing commercial Internet usage and monitoring software product, written for multiple front-end platforms.
- Developed billing and administrative backend, bringing project in on time and within budget.
- User base current of 55,000 customers.

01/1997 to 01/2001

Systems Analyst II New Jersey Institute Of Technology i1/4 Newark, NJ

- Oversee successful requirements gathering of scope/criteria, timeline management, and all phases of development lifecycle.
- Lead projects for external clients for large-scale printing systems; collaborate with developers, stakeholders, internal and external customers.
- Prepared requirements definition documents and requirements traceability matrices.
- Effectively evaluate business needs; analyze processes and workflow to ensure maximum availability through change and problem management review changes effecting complete implementation and test/back out plans.

- Coordinate changes to ensure consistent and repeatable results.
- Identify ways to enhance the customer experience through monitoring of business processes.
- Translate requirements to design and maintain technical specifications.
- Troubleshoot problems and automate manual processes.
- Provide system components, application training, and support to end users.

01/1995 to 01/1997

Network Engineer Electronic Data Systems EDS i1/4 City, STATE

- Certified NetWare Engineer and project lead for EDS/Xerox global sales force automation project.
- Coordinated activities for server and network installation in five Xerox field offices across Michigan and Ohio.

01/1992 to 01/1994

Programmer / Analyst American Community Mutual Insurance i1/4 City, STATE

- Create and customize software applications and tools using waterfall and RAD coding methodologies.
- Manage all phases of application development from requirements elicitation to system design and coding/prototyping, testing, integration, and deployment in PC and mainframe environments.
- Named to organization's programming standards team.

Education

MSc Certificate in Project Management (2015) Preparation coursework for PMP certification UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX 4.0 1999

MSc: Computer Information Systems GRAND VALLEY STATE UNIVERSITY Computer Information Systems Concentrations in object oriented programming and distributed computing. Thesis focused on Java distributed computing technologies. 3.85

BA: Human Resources Management CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY Human Resources Management Senior project examined system delivery models for IT organizations. 4.0

Skills

administrative, agile, application development, automate, automation, billing, budget, business processe, business processes, Business Systems, C++, change management, concept, Critical Thinking, client, clients, delivery, documentation, Engineer, functional, Internet usage, Java, Logic, mainframe, exchange, MSc, network installation, network, NetWare, object oriented programming, payment processing, processes, product manager, coding, Programming, project lead, Project Management, proposals, prototyping, quality, RAD, requirements gathering, requirements definition, sales, SDLC, Software Architecture, SQL, system design, Systems development, Teaching, Troubleshoot, workflow, written